DENIZ MEVLEVIOGLU PhD Candidate

Profile —

A Computer Science PhD candidate at University College Cork, researching real-time anxiety prediction in Virtual Reality Exposure Therapy. Research interests include on-body physiological sensors, machine learning and Virtual Reality. Experienced tutor and demonstrator for varying topics in Computer Science such as web development, authoring and 3D modelling.

_____ Contact ____

Address: Western Gateway Building 1.12

Western Road, Cork

Email: d.mevlevioglu@cs.ucc.ie

Website: denizmev.com

CSS

• PHP

MvSQL

- Academic Research
- Virtual Reality
- Machine Learning
- Tutoring
- Web Development

Skills — Technologies

- Unity
- Java
- Three.js Git
- PythonHTML

- C#
 Keras
 USS
 Blender
 TensorFlow
 JS
 PH SKLearn

——— Languages

- Turkish (Native)
- English (Bilingual)

Publications —

Deniz Mevlevioğlu, Sabin Tabirca, and David Murphy. 2021. Emotional Virtual Reality Stroop Task: Pilot Design. In Proceedings of the 27th ACM Symposium on Virtual Reality Software and Technology (VRST '21). Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, Article 66, 1–3. DOI: 10.1145/3489849.3489952

Deniz Mevlevioğlu, David Murphy, and Sabin Tabirca. 2021. Visual Respiratory Feedback in Virtual Reality Exposure Therapy: A Pilot Study. In ACM International Conference on Interactive Media Experiences (IMX '21), June 21–23, 2021, Virtual Event, USA. ACM, New York, NY, USA 6 Pages. DOI: 10.1145/3452918.3458799

Deniz Mevlevioğlu, David Murphy, and Sabin Tabirca. 2021. In Real-time Anxiety Prediction in Virtual Reality Exposure Therapy. in Adjunct Proceedings of the ACM IMX '21, June 21–23, 2021, New York City, US. DOI: 10.6084/m9.figshare.14699751.v1

Education —

PhD in Computer Science, University College Cork 2020-2024

Thesis title: "Real-time Anxiety prediction in Virtual Reality

Exposure Therapy"

MSc in Interactive Media, University College Cork 2018-2019 1:1 Honours

Thesis title: "Visual respiratory feedback in virtual reality"

BA in Psychology, Bahcesehir University 2012-2016 2.94 GPA

Other Education

2020 **Research Integrity**, Epigeum by Oxford University Press

Specialty Training in Human Subjects Protection

Pedagogical Formation, Marmara University 2018

Professional Memberships

ACM SIGCHI The Special Interest Group on Computer–Human Interaction

IEEE WIE Women in Engineering

Experience –

2020-Present

Tutor, Munster Programming Training by University College Cork

Topics: + Web Development and Design + Databases

Responsibilities:

- Delivered lectures to two classes of approximately 40 secondary school students over the course of 10 weeks
- Provided hands-on tutorials with multiple exercises
- Assigned and graded assignments

Skills and technologies: -HTML -CSS -JavaScript -SQL -MySQL -PHP -Apache

2019-Present

Demonstrator, School of Computer Science, University College Cork

Topics: + Web Development +Authoring +3D Graphics and Modelling +Graphics +Future and Emerging Interaction Technologies +Human-Computer Interaction +Internet-based applications **Responsibilities**:

- Demonstrated for practical sessions to a class of approximately 40 MSc students over the course of one semester
- Delivered tutorials in various topics
- Helped students with problem solving

Skills and technologies: -Virtual Reality -Python -Java -HTML -CSS -JavaScript -PHP -Blender -jQuery -three.js -WebGL

2019-2020

Web Developer, Freelance

Responsibilities:

- Developed and deployed custom personal and e-commerce websites using
- Worked with web designers to synchronize web presence with brand identity and logo.
- Employed search engine optimization tactics to increase reach of targeted audience.

Skills and technologies: -WordPress -HTML -CSS -JavaScript -PHP

2019

Tutor, School of Arts and Humanities, University College Cork

Topic: Concepts and Collaboration in Digital Humanities

Responsibilities:

- Delivered step-by-step tutorials on how to set up a personal website to a class of approximately 40 BA students
- Introduced and familiarised students with technologies useful for academia
- Helped students with problem solving

Skills and technologies: -WordPress -HTML -CSS -Zotero

Activities ——

Student Volunteer Chair, ACM IMX 2022

Acted as a member of the organising committee for ACM Interactive Media Experiences, the leading international conference for research into interactive media experiences.

Guest Lecturer, *University College Cork*

Delivered a guest lecture with the topic "Using Python for Scripting in Blender" to MSc Interactive Media Students, including a tutorial.

Member of Team Xhalers, VR4Rehab Hackathon

Worked with a team of physiotherapists, nurses, physicians and other computer scientists to design and prototype "Short games for long covid"; a VR application for aiding in the management of long-covid symptoms in the VR4Rehab hackathon by Interreg.